Preliminary Guide to the Hannah Green Papers M1030
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Hannah Green papers
circa 1913-2000
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Green, Hannah
M1030
65 Linear Feet (80 boxes)
Papers of American author Hannah Green (1927-1996), including drafts, unpublished writing, and correspondence.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Acquisition Information
Gift of John Wesley, Accn 1998-249, Accn 1999-170, and 2012-064.
Biographical / Historical
Author Hannah Green (1927–1996) was born in Cincinnati, Ohio and lived in Greenwich Village, New York. As an undergraduate at Wellesley, she enrolled in Vladimir Nabokov's survey of Russian literature in translation, which she later wrote about in The New Yorker. Green received her Master of Fine Arts degree at Stanford University with Wallace Stegner. There she met Tillie Olsen, and the two began a lifelong friendship. In 1960, she was a recipient of the first of many MacDowell Colony residencies. Among her published work are the books The Dead of the House (first published by Doubleday in 1972) and Golden Spark, Little Saint: My Book of the Hours of Saint Foy (2000), and the children's book In the City of Paris, as well as articles in The New Yorker. Green taught in the writing programs of Stanford, Columbia and New York University. Until her death from lung cancer in 1996, she was married to the American artist John Wesley.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, notebooks, manuscripts & typescripts, manuscripts of others, articles and reviews, etc.
American literature -- 20th century.; Green, Hannah; Wesley, John, 1928-
- Series 1: Accession 1998-249
  - Correspondence
    - Allen, Sam & Weezie (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Anderson, Tom (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bedway, Barbara (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Black, Michael (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Black, Lucretia (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bolotin, Jay (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Brooks, Peter & Esther (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Crane, Nancy (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Drew, Sandra (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Elman, Richard (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Fisher, Elizabeth (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Fung, Uta & Helmut (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Galtie, Jeanne (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Glasscock, Sarah (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Grchick, Polly ("Poolie") (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Gousha, Joseph ("Jojo") (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Mrs. Alfred M. Allen (Hannah) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Green, Hannah (copies of letters by Hannah Green) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Green, Joseph C. (Uncle Joe) & Aunt G (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Green, Joseph N. (Joe) & Judy (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Green, George (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Green, Mary (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Green, Matthew A. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Green, Robert (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Hall, Macie Green (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Harris, Michael (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Hickler, Sarah (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Hickler, Lonsdale (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Hickler, Luisa (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - L'Heureaux, John (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Llewelyn, John & Margaret (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - MacDowell Colony correspondence (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - MacKenzie, Rachel (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - MacShane, Frank & Lynn (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - McGonigle, Thomas (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - McPherson, Jessamyn (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Morsey, Boo & Sally (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Olsen, Tillie (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Publisher correspondence (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Shattuck, Julie Pratt (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Sherman, Jack (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Shulman, Alix (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Smith, William Jay (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Spender, Stephen (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Spender, Natasha Litvin (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Stegner, Wallace (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Tarnowski, Olga (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Vaughn, Samuel S. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Wesley, John (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Wessel, Peter & Margarita (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Willard (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Bettine & John (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Business correspondence (1) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Business correspondence (2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (1) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (2) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Notes & Postcards (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence to Hannah Green (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Radcliffe (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - RE: Conques correspondence (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Letters about Columbia students (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Mama's Trust (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Grandpa Green's trust & the Southern Ohio Bank (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - NEAH ( Neahtawanta Resort Association) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Photos Summer '72 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Fan letters (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Fan letters - The Dead of the House (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Guggenheim (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Kery, Laszlo Nagyvilag Magazine (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Kessler, Milton "Finding Peace" signed by author (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Krementz, Jill photo (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - MacDowell Colenist (sic) minutes etc. [folder is empty] (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Mr. Nabakov (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Olsen, Tillie (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Schulman, Grace poems (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Wesley, John (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Manuscripts
    - Drafts: Graveyard/The Island/The Kroupa's by H. Green (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Draft & copies: "The Magic Train" or" Hellooo Green Cat" by H. Green (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Draft & notes: A Journal in Praise of the Art of John Wesley (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous working drafts & articles (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Draft: Sainte Foy by H. Green (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous fragments & drafts: various authors + Green (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Papers from college (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Stenographer notebook + miscellaneous items (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "Alice Bony's Book of Cooking" from Hannah's folder (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Catalogs of art exhibitions (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Copies with MS corrections, Chapters 1, 2,3 of "Sainte Foy" (1 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Copies with MS corrections, Chapters 1, 2,3 of "Sainte Foy" (2 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Copies with MS corrections, Chapters 1, 2,3 of "Sainte Foy" (3 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "Golden Spark, Little Saint" parts I,II,III of book 1 (1 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - "Golden Spark, Little Saint" parts I,II,III of book 1 (2 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - "Golden Spark, Little Saint" parts I,II,III of book 1 (3 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - "Golden Spark, Little Saint" photocopies (1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "Golden Spark, Little Saint" photocopies (2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Annotated typescripts "Golden Spark/Sainte Foy" (1 of 4) (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Annotated typescripts "Golden Spark/Sainte Foy" (2 of 4) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Annotated typescripts "Golden Spark/Sainte Foy" (3 of 4) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Annotated typescripts "Golden Spark/Sainte Foy" (4 of 4) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Background material & annotated typescript for Sainte Foy (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Early working copy" - Jan.-Feb. 1978 & Jan. 1979 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Research material/notes "Throne of Wisdom Statue" (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Notebook (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Geography" (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Annotated typescript & notes Chapter 7 (1988) & Chapter III (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "First draft of song notes" (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Bibliographic notes (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Typescript (chapter 1?) revisions (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "Saint Foy's Trial and Her Passion" (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Annotated typescript (1 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Annotated typescript (2 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Annotated typescript (3 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Annotated typescript (4 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Annotated typescript - mixed pages (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Annotated typescript & notes on folder (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - John Wesley letters (in French) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Annotated typescript - notes, part II (1 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Annotated typescript - notes, part II (2 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Annotated typescript - notes, part II (3 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Annotated typescript - Sarah's copy (1 of 5) (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Annotated typescript - Sarah's copy (2 of 5) (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Annotated typescript - Sarah's copy (3 of 5) (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Annotated typescript - Sarah's copy (4 of 5) (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Annotated typescript - Sarah's copy (5 of 5) (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Photocopy of typescript (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - MS notes (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Annotated typescript - photocopy (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Annotated typescript + ms notes & research material (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Annotated typescript & research material (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Annotated typescript end of part III - rough draft (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Typescript photocopy - Chapter 1 revised (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Typescript -end of part III - Sarah's copy (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Annotated typescript - photocopy pgs. 102-289 of "Sainte Foy" (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Early beginning June, July 1977 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Notes: Chapter 1 & Book of Miracles (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Notes: Theft of Bones (?); Pere Andre, Book of Miracles (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Notes on the Tympanum (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Renumbered typanum section for chapter 1 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Research material, Citadel of Blaye & notes chapter 1 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Note on the Song of Sainte Foy (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Chapter III, "Miracle of the Open Door" revisions (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Beginning of chapter III + notes on typanum/Mme. Benoit & others (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Part III opening section + notes on Dadon (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Photocopies of annotated typescript + notes "Sainte Foy" (1 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Photocopies of annotated typescript + notes "Sainte Foy" (2 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Photocopies of annotated typescript + notes "Sainte Foy" (3 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Photocopies of annotated typescript + notes "Sainte Foy" (4 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Annotated typescript/notes/photocopies/loose pages (1 of 4) (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Annotated typescript/notes/photocopies/loose pages (2 of 4) (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Annotated typescript/notes/photocopies/loose pages (3 of 4) (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Annotated typescript/notes/photocopies/loose pages (4 of 4) (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Photocopy of typescript "Golden Spark, Little Saint" (1 of 3) (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Photocopy of typescript "Golden Spark, Little Saint" (2 of 3) (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Photocopy of typescript "Golden Spark, Little Saint" (3 of 3) (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Photocopy of annotated typescript of "Golden Spark" sent to Jane (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Annotated typescript of "Rosalie and her seven gardens." (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 1 + "Rosalie and her seven gardens." (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Typescript: end of chapter III + "Rosalie and her seven gardens." (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Notes on incense + Isaac Vossius (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Annotated typescript, part III + "Madame Fau and the Mer de Ronces." (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Conques: source notes on history and origins (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Notes on "Madame Benoit" (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Annotated typescripts/miscellaneous correspondence/loose papers in box (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Loose pages of typescript, heavily annotated, + MS notes (1 of 6) (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Loose pages of typescript, heavily annotated, + MS notes (2 of 6) (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Loose pages of typescript, heavily annotated, + MS notes (3 of 6) (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Loose pages of typescript, heavily annotated, + MS notes (4 of 6) (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Loose pages of typescript, heavily annotated, + MS notes (5 of 6) (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Loose pages of typescript, heavily annotated, + MS notes (6 of 6) (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Loose pages of annotated typescript + MS notes on the relics of Sainte Foy (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Bernard of Angers & Bishop Fulbert (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Notes on the angels of Albi (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 1 revisions - Charlemagne and the tympanum (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Early version chapter 1 with revised tympanum section (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - First vision/notes on the vision (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Part II, chapter 1 - Pere Andre, Mme. Fau, "ennui", etc. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Photocopy with revisions of 99 page version of "Golden Spark: A Voyage through Conques" (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Saint Foy's birth and her brief life (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Notes from October 1976 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Pere Andre and the tympanum - early notes (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Chanson de Sainte Foy - early notes (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Notes on Charlemagne (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Notes on Guibert the Illumine (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Hannah Green's translation of "The Treasure of Conques" - uncorrected carbon (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Notes on chapter III (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous MS pages/notes/writings/poems (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Photocopy of annotated typescript of Saint Foy May 15, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Photocopy of early version of chapter 1 with annotations (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Complete photocopied typescript with corrections of "Golden Spark, Little Saint" (pgs. 1-114) (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Complete photocopied typescript with corrections of "Golden Spark, Little Saint" (pgs. 115-239) (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Complete photocopied typescript with corrections of "Golden Spark, Little Saint" (pgs. 240-360) (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Complete photocopied typescript with corrections of "Golden Spark, Little Saint" (pgs. 361-470) (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Photocopy of Liber Miraculorum Sancte Fidis by Bouillet (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Photocopies of articles re: touring France (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Photocopied typescript of paper analyzing the reliquary of Saint Foy (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Photocopy of "Texte" (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Photocopy of article "Sulpitius Severus" + Dialogues & letters (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Magazines & news clippings re: Archaeology (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Introduction to Cartulaine (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Scenes & notes for chapter 9 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Photocopied text of The Song of Sainte Foy (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Story about The Fraysou (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous notes on St. Foy + photocopies of front covers of empty folders (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Drafts sent to Hannah Green for review from Tom McGonigle (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy of "Going to Patchogue" by Thomas McGonigle (1 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy of "Going to Patchogue" by Thomas McGonigle (2 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Photocopy of "Going to Patchogue" by Thomas McGonigle (3 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - "To Forget the Future" by Thomas McGonigle (1 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - "To Forget the Future" by Thomas McGonigle (2 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - "To Forget the Future" by Thomas McGonigle (3 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Photocopy of galley pages of "Dawn Powell: At her Best" pgs. 1-14 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy of letter from Dawn Powell re: Joseph "Jo-Jo" Gousha (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy of Dawn Powell's diary from Tim Page (1 of 4) (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Photocopy of Dawn Powell's diary from Tim Page (2 of 4) (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Photocopy of Dawn Powell's diary from Tim Page (3 of 4) (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Photocopy of Dawn Powell's diary from Tim Page (4 of 4) (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Barbara Bedway's review of "Silences" + typescript of two short stories (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Photocopies typescript of short story by Cathy Berger (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Photocopies typescript of "The Substitute" by M.D. Black (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Bound galley proof of "Life Line" by Michael Breslow + correspondence (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Typescript with corrections of "The Children's Ward" by Jane Cooper + correspondence (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Bound typescript of "Cathedral Tree Train" by Richard Elman (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Photocopy of article "Bitch" by Richard Elman (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Typescript of "Our Lady of the Bluebonnets" by Sarah Glasscock + correspondence (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Typescript of short story sent to Hannah Green by Margaret (?) Harrell (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Photocopy of "Feminism and Literature (mainly fiction)" by Florence Howe (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Typescript of "Alarm" by Ruth Josimovich + miscellaneous correspondence (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous writings by William Jay Smith (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Photocopy typescript with corrections of "Army Brat" by William Jay Smith (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Photocopied typescript, heavily annotated, of "Mr. Wilsun and Me" by Therese F. Steiner (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Photocopied typescript of "Hellfire" by Ed Stevens + correspondence (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Photocopy of "Scenario for a Farce" by Brian Swann (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - "Why Chaucer's Wife is from Bath" by Hope Phyllis Weismann - Radcliffe Working Paper Series (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Photocopy of Southern Review story "The Valley Submerged" by Glenway Westcott (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous annotated notes (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Annotated copies of notes sent to Sarah November 1986 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - MS notes, drafts, various stories & chapters (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Notes sent to Sarah (1987 notes) (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - For the notes - mostly chapters 7, 8, 9 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Notes & drafts of various chapters (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Hannah's Notes & drafts (Box 27, Folders 1-6)
    - Notebooks (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - End of chapter III draft (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Notes - chapter IV (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Notes - chapter V (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Notes - chapter VII (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Notes - chapter VIII (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Notes - chapter IX (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Draft pages of "Golden Spark" - mostly hand written (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Draft of first 20 pages of "Golden Spark" with authors cut-and-paste revisions (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Draft of "Golden Spark" sent to Bill with author's corrections (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - For the notes and October notes (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - miscellaneous jottings found amoung Hannah's manuscripts and papers (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - miscellaneous writings (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Notes - Fraysou (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Two English translations of "St. Foy" by DeVilliers + some correspondence (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Draft of the beginning of "Golden Spark" (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - "My Book of Hours of St. Foy" - photocopied typescript with corrections (pages1 - 139) (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Notes - chapter III, drafts & corrections (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Draft of first two chapters sent to Sam, + Nabokov article re: John Wesley (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Notes for chapter 7 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - MS notes & correspondence found within "Hannah's Notes" section (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous writing pads (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Additional notes on the song of St. Foy (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 8 & 9: Babet + the coffre that holds the bones of St. Foy (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Photocopy of article "Translation and the 'Fields of Scripture'" + article on Catholic Saints (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Photocopy of article"Heacenly Images" + article on the tympanum at Conques (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Photocopies of articles on Pierre Soulges/statue of St. Foy (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Notes on the translation of St. Foy d'Agen a Conques (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Book of Miracles + chapters 4, 5, 6 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Photocopy of French language book on St. Foy - pages 3-83 (incomplete) (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy of French language book on St. Foy - pages 88-200 (incomplete) (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy of French language book on St. Foy - pages 201-350 (incomplete) (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Photocopy of French language book on St. Foy - pages 351-634 (incomplete) (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Photocopy of French language book on St. Foy - pages 636-783 (incomplete) (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Photocopy of galleys of "Yonnondido" by Tillie Olsen + Olsen correspondence (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - "Daddy's Papers" Drafts, typescripts, correspondences (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Notebooks (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Photocopies: "Further notes for Sarah" (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Draft typescript, heavily annotated (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - MS notes + notebook (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Draft: annotated typescript of "Courthouse Riot" (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Drafts, notes, typescript of stories (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Draft: annotated typescript of "Dreams & Early Memories" (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Drafts, notes, MS & TS - heavily annotated (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Wellesley memories (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous untitled MS & TS (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Kroupa Material (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous writings, heavily annotated TS & MS (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Speech material for cornerstone laying of library (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Creative Artists Public Service (CAPS) Program: Reading, arrangements, correspondence (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Letter to Joyce: use for teaching Keats (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Russell & Volkening - Summer 1973 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Michael Karoly: Foundation (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Draft for "Hellooo, Green Cat!" (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Aunt Bertie by Sam Kelley (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - "Mr. Nabakov" (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Robert M. Green: MS poetry & correspondence (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Hannah's notes (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Typescript short story: Short Childhood of Francais-Claudius Koenigstein otherwise Ravachol" (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Poetry & miscellaneous writing circa 1974-1976 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Essays: "Mr. Kroupa" - TS, MS, annotated; + "Family" - 3 typescript drafts, ms annotations (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Typescript draft fragments of "Golden Spark, Little Saint" (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Photocopy of short story "The Pilots" by Steve Miller (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Short story collection "Greenwich Time" by various authors (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - "Poolie's Manuscript" (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Photocopy of "Anthology of Troubadour Lyric Poetry" Alan R. Press editor (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Notes on reading- Summer 1976 / Notes on Chapter 1 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Library call numbers, miscellaneous notes (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Addresses/Invitation list (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - "The Dead of the House", blurbs for cover (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - miscellaneous writing & notes (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - MS, typescript heavily annotated, early writing, "Daddy's Death" (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Notebooks (Box 36, Folders 1-6)
    - Notebooks (Box 37, Folders 1-4)
    - Notebooks, notes related to "The Dead of the House" (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Notebooks, notes related to "St. Foy" (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Notebook: August 1964 "MacDowell" (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Notebook: September 1965 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Notebook: September 1965 (2) (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Notebook: July 28, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Notebook: May 1967 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Notebook: Glendale May 15, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Notebook: January 23, 1968 Barrow Street (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Notebook: May 18, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Notebook: March 1969 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Notebook: November 1969 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Notebook: January 1, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 2)